<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hike on The Flying Scotts</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/tags/hike/</link><description>Recent content in Hike on The Flying Scotts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</managingEditor><webMaster>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</webMaster><copyright>2026 The Flying Scotts</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.flying-scotts.uk/tags/hike/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Niue</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/10/6/niue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/10/6/niue/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A belated post about our holiday to the beautiful Pacific island of Niue.
We left Auckland on Saturday on one of the two flights per week (the only flights to Niue from anywhere) and arrived in Niue on Friday, which was a bit strange.
After picking up our hire car (a bit dated) from the airport we headed to the resort.
This was our first encounter with Niue&amp;rsquo;s roads and can be summed up with one word &amp;ndash; potholes!
Nobody seems to drive on the left hand side of the road, instead there are cars swerving all over to avoid the massive potholes that are everywhere.
On the way we passed &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thepuddleniueisland/"&gt;Trevor&lt;/a&gt;, the only duck on Niue, in his pond (large pothole that the fire service top up with water each day).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taranaki Falls loop</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/7/28/taranaki-falls-loop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/7/28/taranaki-falls-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We went to National Park for a long weekend at the end of July, hoping to do some skiing for the first time since moving to New Zealand.
We were able to ski on the first day and, after a couple of times down the beginner&amp;rsquo;s area, I remembered the basics (I haven&amp;rsquo;t done much skiing before and the last time was over 3 years ago) and was able to move on to the next slopes up.
The visibility got pretty bad later in the day but we managed to get quite a lot of runs in and I was feeling much more confident by the end.
Gemma went off by herself for a bit to do some more interesting slopes for her.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tawharanui Regional Park</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/5/20/tawharanui-regional-park/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/5/20/tawharanui-regional-park/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Making the most of a rare weekend off together, we headed up to Tawharanui Regional Park, north of Auckland.
To enter the park we had to pass through a large, automatic gate and fence, designed to keep predators away from the native birds.
It was obviously working as the birds were thriving in the park.
The park is quite a drive from Auckland and there were not many other people around when we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Great Barrier Island Day 2</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/13/great-barrier-island-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/13/great-barrier-island-day-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We spent a windy night in Mt Heale Hut; it seemed like the entire hut was shaking constantly as it was battered by the wind all night.
As you can see in this video it was still pretty windy in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oBzzaL6iSxw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to take South Fork track, instead of heading back up the 1000 steps and taking Kaiaraara track (although perhaps we would have seen some of the Kauri dams if we had gone that way).
South Fork track was very nice and included a one person swing bridge along the way, which was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Great Barrier Island Day 1</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We took advantage of us both having a week off to fly over to Great Barrier Island for a short break.
It was a small plane, with eight seats including the pilot, and looked pretty flimsy.
However we had pretty good weather for the flight across and only got a bit bumpy near the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Small plane" href="../../2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/001_IMG_1099.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/001_IMG_1099_hu_84ea5a07936ca715.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Small plane" alt="Small plane" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Great Barrier we set off walking from the airfield towards the Kaitoke Hot Springs.
It was a flat, easy walk to get there and took around 1.5 hours.
The hot springs were great.
They are natural hot pools with a big pool right next to the main path and a few more smaller pools up the side track, which was where we went.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zion Hill Track</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/3/31/zion-hill-track/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/3/31/zion-hill-track/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the Waitakere Ranges about to close due to Kauri dieback disease, we decided to get one last walk in.
We headed over to Karekare and did a loop starting with the Zion Hill track, down Buck Taylor track and Pararaha Valley track and back along the beach.
The climb up Zion Hill track was mostly a sheltered walk through trees but some points opened out for some great views back to Karekare Beach and on towards Whatipu Beach.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pouakai Tarn and Bell Falls</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/23/pouakai-tarn-and-bell-falls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/23/pouakai-tarn-and-bell-falls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We stopped off in New Plymouth on our way back up to Auckland, near the end of our holiday.
We got there just after some bad weather (ex-cyclone Gita) passed through but luckily we missed the worst of it.
Water restrictions and a boil water notice were in place and Egmont National Park was closed the first day we were there.
Fortunately we were staying in New Plymouth for three days and we decided to wait until our final day to go into the park, hoping the tracks would be in better condition by then.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abel Tasman Day 3</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/18/abel-tasman-day-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/18/abel-tasman-day-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It was an early start this morning as we had to make it across the estuary within 2 hours of low tide (5:20 am).
We were up around 6 and, luckily, were getting more efficient at making breakfast (porridge) and packing our bags ready to leave.
The sign in the hut said that, even at low tide, you should expect to get wet, so we took off our shoes and walked across (~1 km) barefoot.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t very comfortable as there were lots of sharp stones/shells on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abel Tasman Day 2</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/17/abel-tasman-day-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/17/abel-tasman-day-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was our second day hiking through Abel Tasman, heading from Bark Bay Hut to Awaroa Hut, about half the distance we covered on the previous day.
We started fairly early as somebody staying at the hut, but travelling in the opposite direction, had mentioned there was a big hill to begin with, and we wanted to get that out of the way before it started getting too hot.
It was quite a big hill but the view down to the next beach was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abel Tasman Day 1</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/16/abel-tasman-day-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/16/abel-tasman-day-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We began our holiday by flying down to Nelson in the early morning and picking up our hire car.
We headed over towards Marahau, where we were starting the hike the next day.
It was an early start as when we booked the accommodation the first hut was already full, so the plan was to walk from Marahau to Bark Bay Hut (with the option of a couple of side tracks along the way) on the first day.
The weather was great and we started the walk at sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mt Crichton Loop Track</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I took advantage of a conference in Queenstown to walk the &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/otago/places/queenstown-area/things-to-do/mt-crichton-loop-track/"&gt;Mt Crichton Loop Track&lt;/a&gt;.
Unfortunately the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t great, with a bit of rain, but that gave me an opportunity to try out my new waterproof trousers.
I did the loop in an anticlockwise direction, which meant walking up through forest and past the Lake Dispute turn off in the first half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Walking up through the forest" href="../../2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/001_track.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/001_track_hu_f308f554f197aa59.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Walking up through the forest" alt="Walking up through the forest" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half of the walk included an old gold miner&amp;rsquo;s hut.
The hut is kept in good condition and there was somebody cooking breakfast in there, having spent the night, when I passed by.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Waitawa Regional Park</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had Gemma&amp;rsquo;s dad and family visiting over Christmas and decided to head over to Waitawa Regional Park for the first time.
As we drove through to the car park there were great views over the coastline.
We walked the &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/cmsfiles/files/Explore%20Waitawa%20by%20foot%20map%20-%20including%20care%20code.pdf"&gt;Puweto Loop&lt;/a&gt;, which goes around the outer edge of the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Waitawa Regional Park" href="../../2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/001_view-from-walk.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/001_view-from-walk_hu_cc0c6f5254ef0c16.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Waitawa Regional Park" alt="Waitawa Regional Park" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginning of the walk was really impressive, starting by walking along the coast, down to the beaches and up along the tops of the cliffs.
Next to one beach we passed a sea kayak &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/waitawa/waitawa-bay-sea-kayak-campground"&gt;campground&lt;/a&gt;, part of the 5 day sea kayak &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/articles/te-ara-moana-the-sea-going-pathway"&gt;trail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hooker Valley Track</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The weather seemed a bit less cloudy when we got up this morning but as we drove from the campsite towards White Horse Hill Campground, where the &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/canterbury/places/aoraki-mount-cook-national-park/things-to-do/tracks/hooker-valley-track/"&gt;Hooker Valley Track&lt;/a&gt; starts, the clouds closed in.
Our legs were still tired from the two big walks we had done already, so we were glad that the track was only 10 km and quite flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Hooker Valley Track" href="../../2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/001_hooker-valley-track.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/001_hooker-valley-track_hu_670977986e07a091.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Hooker Valley Track" alt="Hooker Valley Track" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three swing bridges along the track, which were quite impressive.
At the end of the track is Hooker Lake, which has lots of small icebergs floating around it, coming from the glacier at the far end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roys Peak, Wanaka</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On the second day of our holiday we were up early in the morning to tackle &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/otago/places/wanaka-area/things-to-do/roys-peak-track/"&gt;Roys Peak&lt;/a&gt;, just outside Wanaka.
Once again we were lucky to have clear blue skies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Lake Wanaka in the morning" href="../../2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/001_lake-wanaka.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/001_lake-wanaka_hu_d004ab77cc88eb4f.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Lake Wanaka in the morning" alt="Lake Wanaka in the morning" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set off early in the hope of missing the worst heat of the day but it was already getting hot at 7:30am.
The track started off steep and stayed that way all the way to the top, with no shade along the way.
However it was much less technical than the climb up Ben Lomond the previous day.
There were some great views from the lookouts on the way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ben Lomond</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/18/ben-lomond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/18/ben-lomond/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was the first day of our holiday in the South Island. We arrived in Queenstown in the morning with the usual great views from the plane during the approach.
Picking up our campervan we made our way through a very busy Queenstown (marathon day) and parked up at the bottom of the hike up to &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/otago/places/queenstown-area/things-to-do/ben-lomond-track/"&gt;Ben Lomond&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="435x580" data-title="Queenstown approach" href="../../2017/11/18/ben-lomond/099_IMG_20171118_085954.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/18/ben-lomond/099_IMG_20171118_085954_hu_32b972b90b37afd3.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Queenstown approach" alt="Queenstown approach" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 11:30 by the time we started and it was very hot with perfect, clear skies.
The bottom section of the walk was through forest and was quite technical and steep, although the shade was very welcome.
As we made it up and out of the forest we were rewarded with great views back over Lake Wakatipu and continued on to the saddle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kura - Omanawanui Loop</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/24/kura-omanawanui-loop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/24/kura-omanawanui-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was a great walk. We had been to Whatipu beach before and really liked it there, so decided
to head back and do a walk. We started from Whatipu and took the
&lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/whatipu/track/Kura%20Track"&gt;Kura track&lt;/a&gt; first. This
track winds its way up through a forest and involved a few stream crossings. At the first of these
there were stepping stones so we spent time trying to get across without getting our feet wet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tongariro Crossing</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months after arriving in New Zealand we travelled south to do the &lt;a href="http://www.tongarirocrossing.org.nz/"&gt;Tongariro Crossing&lt;/a&gt;, supposedly one of the best single day hikes you can do. It was an early start as we had to drop our car off at the finish point and then get a bus to the start. It was very busy due to the good weather and it was also a long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1280" data-title="At the start of the Tongariro Crossing" href="../../2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/001_start.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/001_start_hu_69db7a15aecbb40e.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="At the start of the Tongariro Crossing" alt="At the start of the Tongariro Crossing" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walk was amazing, passing by active volcanoes, and the scenery was incredible. We were pretty lucky with the weather although there were some low clouds.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>