<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Activities on The Flying Scotts</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/categories/activities/</link><description>Recent content in Activities on The Flying Scotts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</managingEditor><webMaster>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</webMaster><copyright>2026 The Flying Scotts</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.flying-scotts.uk/categories/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wanaka to Hawea bike</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2021/6/28/wanaka-to-hawea-bike/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2021/6/28/wanaka-to-hawea-bike/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One morning in Wanaka, we hired a couple of mountain bikes and cycled out to Lake Hawea and back.
It was a cold start to the day and took us a long time to warm up.
We set out from Wanaka and cycled along a trail following the edge of the lake.
When we reached the lake outlet the trail passed through a campsite we had stayed in previously, after which it narrowed down for a more technical section.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Twin Coast Cycle Trail</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2020/11/22/twin-coast-cycle-trail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2020/11/22/twin-coast-cycle-trail/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We hired mountain bikes near the finish and they dropped us off at the start for the long cycle back.
They&amp;rsquo;d given us a code to lock the bikes up so we weren&amp;rsquo;t in a rush to get back before they closed.
There was a good climb in the first half and it rained quite heavily during that part but eventually cleared up and was a nice day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section id='post-route-0' class="gpx" data-gpx-source="twin-coast-cycle-trail.gpx" data-map-target='post-map-0' data-title='Twin Coast Cycle Trail'&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;a href="twin-coast-cycle-trail.gpx" title="Download GPX file"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Loading...&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class="start"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;div class="map" id='post-map-0'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;ul class="info"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distance:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="distance"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;km&lt;/li&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;li&gt;Duration:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="duration"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;li&gt;Pace:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="pace"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;/km&lt;/li&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;li&gt;Ascent:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="ascent"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;m&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description></item><item><title>Paihia Kayak</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2020/11/21/paihia-kayak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2020/11/21/paihia-kayak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On a short trip up to Bay of Islands we hired a double kayak for a few hours.
The weather was really good and we headed first up the Waitangi river to Haruru falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3ClhFQagoys?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back out of Waitangi river into the bay we headed around a small island to stop on the beach for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Goldie Bush</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2019/1/1/goldie-bush/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2019/1/1/goldie-bush/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day we headed over to &lt;a href="https://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/auckland/places/muriwai-and-te-henga-area/tracks/goldie-bush-walkway/"&gt;Goldie Bush&lt;/a&gt; for a run.
We set off from the Horsman Road entrance and turned left early on to head towards the Constable Road entrance.
These wide, gravel tracks have recently been upgraded to try and prevent Kauri dieback from spreading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Goldie Bush" href="../../2019/1/1/goldie-bush/001_IMG_20190101_091120.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2019/1/1/goldie-bush/001_IMG_20190101_091120_hu_c4d32e52711f5e6c.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Goldie Bush" alt="Goldie Bush" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We crossed over the suspension bridge and did an out and back section up to the other entrance, before heading down to &lt;a href="https://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/auckland/places/muriwai-and-te-henga-area/tracks/mokoroa-stream-track/"&gt;Mokoroa stream&lt;/a&gt; for the return leg.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Niue</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/10/6/niue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/10/6/niue/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A belated post about our holiday to the beautiful Pacific island of Niue.
We left Auckland on Saturday on one of the two flights per week (the only flights to Niue from anywhere) and arrived in Niue on Friday, which was a bit strange.
After picking up our hire car (a bit dated) from the airport we headed to the resort.
This was our first encounter with Niue&amp;rsquo;s roads and can be summed up with one word &amp;ndash; potholes!
Nobody seems to drive on the left hand side of the road, instead there are cars swerving all over to avoid the massive potholes that are everywhere.
On the way we passed &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thepuddleniueisland/"&gt;Trevor&lt;/a&gt;, the only duck on Niue, in his pond (large pothole that the fire service top up with water each day).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wairoa Loop Track</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/9/8/wairoa-loop-track/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/9/8/wairoa-loop-track/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back to the Hunua Ranges for another run, this time on the Suspension Bridge and Wairoa Loop tracks. The start of the Suspension Bridge track was steep and slow but the narrow track through the forest was nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Suspension Bridge" href="../../2018/9/8/wairoa-loop-track/002_suspension-bridge.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2018/9/8/wairoa-loop-track/002_suspension-bridge_hu_c044ddece8e2caf.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Suspension Bridge" alt="Suspension Bridge" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the steep climb up this track, there was a steep descent down towards Wairoa Reservoir. On the way down there was a nice lookout point.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taranaki Falls loop</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/7/28/taranaki-falls-loop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/7/28/taranaki-falls-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We went to National Park for a long weekend at the end of July, hoping to do some skiing for the first time since moving to New Zealand.
We were able to ski on the first day and, after a couple of times down the beginner&amp;rsquo;s area, I remembered the basics (I haven&amp;rsquo;t done much skiing before and the last time was over 3 years ago) and was able to move on to the next slopes up.
The visibility got pretty bad later in the day but we managed to get quite a lot of runs in and I was feeling much more confident by the end.
Gemma went off by herself for a bit to do some more interesting slopes for her.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pukapuka Track loop</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/6/30/pukapuka-track-loop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/6/30/pukapuka-track-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It was a cold start to the morning as we headed over to the Hunua Ranges to go for a run on some new trails.
The temperature dropped to -2° at the lowest point and it was quite misty when we arrived.
We set off from the car park below Upper Mangatawhiri Dam, through the campsite and onto A.R.A. Drive.
A short way along there we turned off onto River Track, which was more interesting than the road, and included a little stream crossing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ernies Track loop</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/6/16/ernies-track-loop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/6/16/ernies-track-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another set of weekend night shifts for Gemma and another trip to the Hunua Ranges for me.
This time I headed to the Upper Mangatawhiri Reservoir, parking below the dam near the campsite, to do the Ernies Track loop.
I did the loop in a clockwise direction, which I think was a good decision.
This way, most of the downhill was on wide, open track, while the uphill was steep and technical.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hunua Falls loop</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/6/9/hunua-falls-loop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/6/9/hunua-falls-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With Gemma sleeping after a night shift I decided it would be best to get out of the house and headed down to the Hunua Ranges for the first time.
Starting from Hunua Falls, I did a loop around Cosseys Gorge track and Massey track.
It was a popular spot, with a full car park and lots of people, at least around the waterfall area.
After passing through the Kauri dieback cleaning station I headed out on the Cosseys Gorge track, doing the loop in a clockwise direction.
Near the beginning, there was a little stream crossing, followed by a nice run beside a river and a gentle climb up towards the reservoir.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tawharanui Regional Park</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/5/20/tawharanui-regional-park/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/5/20/tawharanui-regional-park/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Making the most of a rare weekend off together, we headed up to Tawharanui Regional Park, north of Auckland.
To enter the park we had to pass through a large, automatic gate and fence, designed to keep predators away from the native birds.
It was obviously working as the birds were thriving in the park.
The park is quite a drive from Auckland and there were not many other people around when we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Great Barrier Island Day 2</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/13/great-barrier-island-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/13/great-barrier-island-day-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We spent a windy night in Mt Heale Hut; it seemed like the entire hut was shaking constantly as it was battered by the wind all night.
As you can see in this video it was still pretty windy in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oBzzaL6iSxw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to take South Fork track, instead of heading back up the 1000 steps and taking Kaiaraara track (although perhaps we would have seen some of the Kauri dams if we had gone that way).
South Fork track was very nice and included a one person swing bridge along the way, which was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Great Barrier Island Day 1</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We took advantage of us both having a week off to fly over to Great Barrier Island for a short break.
It was a small plane, with eight seats including the pilot, and looked pretty flimsy.
However we had pretty good weather for the flight across and only got a bit bumpy near the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Small plane" href="../../2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/001_IMG_1099.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2018/4/12/great-barrier-island-day-1/001_IMG_1099_hu_84ea5a07936ca715.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Small plane" alt="Small plane" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Great Barrier we set off walking from the airfield towards the Kaitoke Hot Springs.
It was a flat, easy walk to get there and took around 1.5 hours.
The hot springs were great.
They are natural hot pools with a big pool right next to the main path and a few more smaller pools up the side track, which was where we went.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Zion Hill Track</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/3/31/zion-hill-track/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/3/31/zion-hill-track/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With the Waitakere Ranges about to close due to Kauri dieback disease, we decided to get one last walk in.
We headed over to Karekare and did a loop starting with the Zion Hill track, down Buck Taylor track and Pararaha Valley track and back along the beach.
The climb up Zion Hill track was mostly a sheltered walk through trees but some points opened out for some great views back to Karekare Beach and on towards Whatipu Beach.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pouakai Tarn and Bell Falls</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/23/pouakai-tarn-and-bell-falls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/23/pouakai-tarn-and-bell-falls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We stopped off in New Plymouth on our way back up to Auckland, near the end of our holiday.
We got there just after some bad weather (ex-cyclone Gita) passed through but luckily we missed the worst of it.
Water restrictions and a boil water notice were in place and Egmont National Park was closed the first day we were there.
Fortunately we were staying in New Plymouth for three days and we decided to wait until our final day to go into the park, hoping the tracks would be in better condition by then.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abel Tasman Day 3</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/18/abel-tasman-day-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/18/abel-tasman-day-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It was an early start this morning as we had to make it across the estuary within 2 hours of low tide (5:20 am).
We were up around 6 and, luckily, were getting more efficient at making breakfast (porridge) and packing our bags ready to leave.
The sign in the hut said that, even at low tide, you should expect to get wet, so we took off our shoes and walked across (~1 km) barefoot.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t very comfortable as there were lots of sharp stones/shells on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abel Tasman Day 2</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/17/abel-tasman-day-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/17/abel-tasman-day-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was our second day hiking through Abel Tasman, heading from Bark Bay Hut to Awaroa Hut, about half the distance we covered on the previous day.
We started fairly early as somebody staying at the hut, but travelling in the opposite direction, had mentioned there was a big hill to begin with, and we wanted to get that out of the way before it started getting too hot.
It was quite a big hill but the view down to the next beach was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abel Tasman Day 1</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/16/abel-tasman-day-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/16/abel-tasman-day-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We began our holiday by flying down to Nelson in the early morning and picking up our hire car.
We headed over towards Marahau, where we were starting the hike the next day.
It was an early start as when we booked the accommodation the first hut was already full, so the plan was to walk from Marahau to Bark Bay Hut (with the option of a couple of side tracks along the way) on the first day.
The weather was great and we started the walk at sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mt Crichton Loop Track</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I took advantage of a conference in Queenstown to walk the &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/otago/places/queenstown-area/things-to-do/mt-crichton-loop-track/"&gt;Mt Crichton Loop Track&lt;/a&gt;.
Unfortunately the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t great, with a bit of rain, but that gave me an opportunity to try out my new waterproof trousers.
I did the loop in an anticlockwise direction, which meant walking up through forest and past the Lake Dispute turn off in the first half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Walking up through the forest" href="../../2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/001_track.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2018/2/11/mt-crichton-loop-track/001_track_hu_f308f554f197aa59.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Walking up through the forest" alt="Walking up through the forest" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second half of the walk included an old gold miner&amp;rsquo;s hut.
The hut is kept in good condition and there was somebody cooking breakfast in there, having spent the night, when I passed by.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mokoroa Falls</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/6/mokoroa-falls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/2/6/mokoroa-falls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Unusually we both had the day off on a public holiday and we decided to walk to the &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/auckland/places/muriwai-and-te-henga-area/tracks/mokoroa-falls-track/"&gt;Mokoroa Falls&lt;/a&gt; in the Waitakeres.
It is an easy walk along a good track and the falls are quite impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1440x1920" data-title="Looking down at Mokoroa Falls" href="../../2018/2/6/mokoroa-falls/002_mokoroa-falls-above.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2018/2/6/mokoroa-falls/002_mokoroa-falls-above_hu_e0ab55fe63347516.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Looking down at Mokoroa Falls" alt="Looking down at Mokoroa Falls" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short extra walk down some steps takes you to the bottom of the falls.
We managed to keep our feet dry crossing the rocks to get to the viewing point.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/1/13/gold-coast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2018/1/13/gold-coast/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Gemma had to go to Gold Coast for work so we decided to head out together a few days early and have a look around.
We went on a boat trip to Moreton Island and did some snorkelling around some ship wrecks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Moreton Island" href="../../2018/1/13/gold-coast/003_us-on-beach.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2018/1/13/gold-coast/003_us-on-beach_hu_221a5f21f4089b62.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Moreton Island" alt="Moreton Island" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The island was stunning and we spent some time on a beautiful beach.
The snorkelling was really cool and we got to see lots of fish and coral around the wrecks (see video below).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tiritiri Matangi Island</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/28/tiritiri-matangi-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/28/tiritiri-matangi-island/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;During the holidays we decided to head to &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/auckland/places/tiritiri-matangi-scientific-reserve-open-sanctuary/"&gt;Tiritiri Matangi Island&lt;/a&gt; for the first time, with Gemma&amp;rsquo;s family.
We took the ferry from Auckland, which took around 75 minutes, and was quite rough and windy. After departing the boat everyone split into small groups (the 6 of us were one group) for the guided tour.
The tour is definitely worthwhile if you have not been to the island before as you see lots of things you might have missed otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Waitawa Regional Park</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had Gemma&amp;rsquo;s dad and family visiting over Christmas and decided to head over to Waitawa Regional Park for the first time.
As we drove through to the car park there were great views over the coastline.
We walked the &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/cmsfiles/files/Explore%20Waitawa%20by%20foot%20map%20-%20including%20care%20code.pdf"&gt;Puweto Loop&lt;/a&gt;, which goes around the outer edge of the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Waitawa Regional Park" href="../../2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/001_view-from-walk.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/12/27/waitawa-regional-park/001_view-from-walk_hu_cc0c6f5254ef0c16.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Waitawa Regional Park" alt="Waitawa Regional Park" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginning of the walk was really impressive, starting by walking along the coast, down to the beaches and up along the tops of the cliffs.
Next to one beach we passed a sea kayak &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/waitawa/waitawa-bay-sea-kayak-campground"&gt;campground&lt;/a&gt;, part of the 5 day sea kayak &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/articles/te-ara-moana-the-sea-going-pathway"&gt;trail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fairy Falls</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/26/fairy-falls/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/26/fairy-falls/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a nice easy walk down to Fairy Falls and it is one of the usual places we take visitors.
This time we were with Gemma&amp;rsquo;s Dad and his family, who were visiting us for Christmas.
The track is all downhill on the way there and eventually you reach a little stream crossing followed by the upper falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1440x1920" data-title="Upper falls" href="../../2017/12/26/fairy-falls/099_upper-falls.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/12/26/fairy-falls/099_upper-falls_hu_8630b01ac7ab13f5.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Upper falls" alt="Upper falls" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that there are a lot of steps taking you down to the base of the main waterfall.
From the bottom of the waterfall you can either return back up the steps or continue on the path along the stream and loop back round on the road (we haven&amp;rsquo;t tried this yet).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exploring Browns Island</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/3/exploring-browns-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/12/3/exploring-browns-island/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The weather was looking really calm and we both had the day off so we loaded the kayaks onto the car and headed over to St Heliers, to kayak around Browns Island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="St Heliers" href="../../2017/12/3/exploring-browns-island/001_st-heliers-beach.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/12/3/exploring-browns-island/001_st-heliers-beach_hu_81417598d5e6578c.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="St Heliers" alt="St Heliers" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really smooth paddle over to Browns Island.
We approached the western side of the island and then started around the island in a clockwise direction.
We landed at Crater Bay, on the north-eastern corner, and had the beach to ourselves to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Akaroa Kayak with Dolphins</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/24/akaroa-kayak-with-dolphins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/24/akaroa-kayak-with-dolphins/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On the final day of our holiday in the South Island we went &lt;a href="http://akaroakayaks.com/sunrise-wildlife/"&gt;kayaking&lt;/a&gt; near Akaroa.
The weather was a bit cloudy but that was good as it would hopefully keep us a bit cooler.
We got out in our kayak first and while waiting for the others we heard a lot of screaming coming from the shore.
It turns out a couple of the people realised they were afraid of the water; we were lucky they gave up in the end otherwise it would have been a very slow trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Round the Mountain</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/23/round-the-mountain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/23/round-the-mountain/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We had an early start this morning for the drive from Tekapo to Akaroa, near Christchurch.
We arrived around midday and after a bite to eat and a quick stroll through the town we decided to run/walk around the &lt;a href="https://www.bankspeninsulawalks.co.nz/akaroa-walks/"&gt;Round the Mountain&lt;/a&gt; track.
This gave me a chance to try running with my new backpack and Inov-8 Roclite 325 shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="We felt old going up this hill" href="../../2017/11/23/round-the-mountain/001_feeling-old.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/23/round-the-mountain/001_feeling-old_hu_207178308f09e6b5.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="We felt old going up this hill" alt="We felt old going up this hill" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The climb out of Akaroa was steep and went on for a long time.
We certainly felt old on the way up (see photo).
Running in the middle of the day wasn&amp;rsquo;t ideal and we were suffering from the heat.
Thankfully we were rewarded with great views from the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mt John Observatory</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/22/mt-john-observatory/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/22/mt-john-observatory/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We started this day very early - around 1am!
We were booked onto a stargazing tour at the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_John_University_Observatory"&gt;Mt John Observatory&lt;/a&gt; near Lake Tekapo, which started at 1:30am.
The tour was great!
We were very lucky and had perfect clear skies and conditions for seeing the night sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1280" data-title="Star gazing" href="../../2017/11/22/mt-john-observatory/001_night-sky-1.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/22/mt-john-observatory/001_night-sky-1_hu_df0c6ef2f94d0351.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Star gazing" alt="Star gazing" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1280" data-title="Star gazing 2" href="../../2017/11/22/mt-john-observatory/002_night-sky-2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/22/mt-john-observatory/002_night-sky-2_hu_dbd2528f4df00bf8.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Star gazing 2" alt="Star gazing 2" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After catching up on some much needed sleep later in the morning, we headed part way round Lake Tekapo to go for a run.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hooker Valley Track</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The weather seemed a bit less cloudy when we got up this morning but as we drove from the campsite towards White Horse Hill Campground, where the &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/canterbury/places/aoraki-mount-cook-national-park/things-to-do/tracks/hooker-valley-track/"&gt;Hooker Valley Track&lt;/a&gt; starts, the clouds closed in.
Our legs were still tired from the two big walks we had done already, so we were glad that the track was only 10 km and quite flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Hooker Valley Track" href="../../2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/001_hooker-valley-track.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/21/hooker-valley-track/001_hooker-valley-track_hu_670977986e07a091.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Hooker Valley Track" alt="Hooker Valley Track" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three swing bridges along the track, which were quite impressive.
At the end of the track is Hooker Lake, which has lots of small icebergs floating around it, coming from the glacier at the far end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lake Wanaka Kayak</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/20/lake-wanaka-kayak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/20/lake-wanaka-kayak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After two big walks in two days our legs were feeling very tired, so we decided to give them a rest and do some kayaking.
We hired a double kayak and set off on a very peaceful and stunning day on Lake Wanaka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Kayaking on Lake Wanaka" href="../../2017/11/20/lake-wanaka-kayak/001_gem-paddle.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/20/lake-wanaka-kayak/001_gem-paddle_hu_158fb01435fa193e.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Kayaking on Lake Wanaka" alt="Kayaking on Lake Wanaka" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We paddled up the edge of the lake and then cut across to Ruby Island.
We did a full circuit of the island and then landed on a beach and had a look around and walked to the top of the island.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roys Peak, Wanaka</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On the second day of our holiday we were up early in the morning to tackle &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/otago/places/wanaka-area/things-to-do/roys-peak-track/"&gt;Roys Peak&lt;/a&gt;, just outside Wanaka.
Once again we were lucky to have clear blue skies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Lake Wanaka in the morning" href="../../2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/001_lake-wanaka.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/19/roys-peak-wanaka/001_lake-wanaka_hu_d004ab77cc88eb4f.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Lake Wanaka in the morning" alt="Lake Wanaka in the morning" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set off early in the hope of missing the worst heat of the day but it was already getting hot at 7:30am.
The track started off steep and stayed that way all the way to the top, with no shade along the way.
However it was much less technical than the climb up Ben Lomond the previous day.
There were some great views from the lookouts on the way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ben Lomond</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/18/ben-lomond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/18/ben-lomond/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was the first day of our holiday in the South Island. We arrived in Queenstown in the morning with the usual great views from the plane during the approach.
Picking up our campervan we made our way through a very busy Queenstown (marathon day) and parked up at the bottom of the hike up to &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/otago/places/queenstown-area/things-to-do/ben-lomond-track/"&gt;Ben Lomond&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="435x580" data-title="Queenstown approach" href="../../2017/11/18/ben-lomond/099_IMG_20171118_085954.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/18/ben-lomond/099_IMG_20171118_085954_hu_32b972b90b37afd3.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Queenstown approach" alt="Queenstown approach" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 11:30 by the time we started and it was very hot with perfect, clear skies.
The bottom section of the walk was through forest and was quite technical and steep, although the shade was very welcome.
As we made it up and out of the forest we were rewarded with great views back over Lake Wakatipu and continued on to the saddle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Karamatura Falls Walk</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/12/karamatura-falls-walk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/11/12/karamatura-falls-walk/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We walked the &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/huia/track/Karamatura%20Loop%20Walk"&gt;Karamatura Loop walk&lt;/a&gt;, a short walk through forest starting just past Huia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1440x1920" data-title="Karamatura Falls" href="../../2017/11/12/karamatura-falls-walk/002_karamatura-falls.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/12/karamatura-falls-walk/002_karamatura-falls_hu_c8dbf130d9fbda41.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Karamatura Falls" alt="Karamatura Falls" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a nice walk and we extended it a bit to carry on to the Karamatura Falls, where we got to test our new GoPro.
This last section was a bit more technical, with some clambering over rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Karamatura Falls" href="../../2017/11/12/karamatura-falls-walk/003_infront-of-falls.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/11/12/karamatura-falls-walk/003_infront-of-falls_hu_7f33f10d57e86a6d.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Karamatura Falls" alt="Karamatura Falls" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was time to stop in Huia on the way home for an ice cream on the beach.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cathedral Cove</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/9/24/cathedral-cove/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/9/24/cathedral-cove/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We spent a nice weekend away in the Coromandel, near Whitianga. We arrived on the Saturday and walked out to Cathedral Cove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Cathedral Cove" href="../../2017/9/24/cathedral-cove/002_cathedral-cove.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/9/24/cathedral-cove/002_cathedral-cove_hu_f725a823a3fc44ab.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Cathedral Cove" alt="Cathedral Cove" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was busy but there were amazing views, especially from the side track to the lookout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Cathedral Cove walk lookout" href="../../2017/9/24/cathedral-cove/003_lookout.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/9/24/cathedral-cove/003_lookout_hu_f6a8436810f5f4ef.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Cathedral Cove walk lookout" alt="Cathedral Cove walk lookout" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also paid a quick visit to Gemstone Bay.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mercer Bay Loop Walk</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/8/13/mercer-bay-loop-walk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/8/13/mercer-bay-loop-walk/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We went for a short walk around the &lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/karekare/track/Mercer%20Bay%20Loop%20Walk"&gt;Mercer Bay Loop&lt;/a&gt;.
We were out for about 1 hour and will definitely go back to do a longer one on part of the Hillary trail, as the area looked stunning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Mercer Bay" href="../../2017/8/13/mercer-bay-loop-walk/001_mercer-bay.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/8/13/mercer-bay-loop-walk/001_mercer-bay_hu_b8844a95ebeb0d.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Mercer Bay" alt="Mercer Bay" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id='post-route-0' class="gpx" data-lat="-36.97017" data-lon="174.46821" data-map-target='post-map-0' data-title='Mercer Bay Loop Walk'&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Loading...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class="start"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;div class="map" id='post-map-0'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description></item><item><title>Around Browns Island</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/6/17/around-browns-island/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/6/17/around-browns-island/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Setting off from the western end of Mission Bay, I kayaked around Browns Island for the first time.
The weather was stunning, just a very light wind and lots of sun, although it wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly warm.
There was still a bit of mist in the distance when I set off but it looked like it would burn off soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Departing" href="../../2017/6/17/around-browns-island/001_mission-bay.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/6/17/around-browns-island/001_mission-bay_hu_4ce06c612ce9c1a2.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Departing" alt="Departing" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the buoys along the coast past Kohimarama and St Heliers, I reached Achilles Point in what seemed like no time.
From there I headed out towards Browns Island (you can just make out Browns Island in the image below, surrounded by fog).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Whangaparoa Head</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/6/11/whangaparoa-head/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/6/11/whangaparoa-head/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After unloading the kayaks at Matakatia beach, driving across to the finish point at Tindalls Beach and walking back to the start point, we set off for a kayak around Whangaparoa Head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Army Bay for lunch" href="../../2017/6/11/whangaparoa-head/002_army-bay.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/6/11/whangaparoa-head/002_army-bay_hu_a947fe0badae854b.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Army Bay for lunch" alt="Army Bay for lunch" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first half we were quite exposed to the wind and it got a bit choppy. After going around the head we were sheltered from the wind and it was a very pleasant paddle back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>French Bay Kayak</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/5/28/french-bay-kayak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/5/28/french-bay-kayak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We finally bought Gemma a kayak too - a (very) old Puffin - and this was our first trip out together.
We went from French Bay, which is only a 5-10 minute drive from home, and is very nice to paddle from when the wind and tide are OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="French Bay launching" href="../../2017/5/28/french-bay-kayak/001_launching.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/5/28/french-bay-kayak/001_launching_hu_6c37e0b86800f15a.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="French Bay launching" alt="French Bay launching" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hugged the coast on the way to Blockhouse Bay, looking at all the little beaches and bays along the way, and then took a more direct route on the way back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Milford to Long Bay</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/5/6/milford-to-long-bay/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/5/6/milford-to-long-bay/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was the longest kayak I have done so far. We went from the north end of Milford Beach all the way up the coast to Long Bay and back. The weather was perfect, with clear blue skies and the sea was almost flat. The coast was quite impressive in places, with lots of cliffs with houses perched on the edge (they must have some amazing views). There were also lots of slips from the recent bad weather.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taupo Rock Carvings</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/3/2/taupo-rock-carvings/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2017/3/2/taupo-rock-carvings/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Gemma and Victoria were going to do Tongariro crossing again but I had injured my ankle so decided to go kayaking instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1425" data-title="Lake Taupo" href="../../2017/3/2/taupo-rock-carvings/003_landing.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/3/2/taupo-rock-carvings/003_landing_hu_3fed0e3984173c11.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Lake Taupo" alt="Lake Taupo" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a quick search I found the Maori Rock Carvings which was an 18 km trip out and back from a kayak hire place on the beach at Taupo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1425" data-title="Maori Rock Carvings" href="../../2017/3/2/taupo-rock-carvings/002_rock-carvings.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2017/3/2/taupo-rock-carvings/002_rock-carvings_hu_a1b8f89210339054.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Maori Rock Carvings" alt="Maori Rock Carvings" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the kayak for 5 hours but didn&amp;rsquo;t hang around and got back in under 3.5. It was a nice day to paddle, with not much wind, and was the longest I had spent kayaking in one go, with only a brief stop at the carvings to take a photo and have something to eat and drink. By the time I returned my back was pretty sore!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Waiheke Kayak</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/30/waiheke-kayak/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/30/waiheke-kayak/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On one of our days off over the Christmas break we headed to Waiheke Island and went on a guided kayak tour with &lt;a href="http://www.kayakwaiheke.co.nz/"&gt;Kayak Waiheke&lt;/a&gt;. We ended up in a double kayak and there was one other pair on the trip with us. The weather was perfect and there was amazing scenery as we kayaked along the coast. There were some incredible houses on the cliff tops overlooking the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1425" data-title="Private beach for lunch" href="../../2016/12/30/waiheke-kayak/002_beach.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/12/30/waiheke-kayak/002_beach_hu_22c0d5631a2ad067.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Private beach for lunch" alt="Private beach for lunch" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped for lunch on a stunning little beach, which we had to ourselves. There was even time to go for a short swim in the sea before heading back the way we came.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kura - Omanawanui Loop</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/24/kura-omanawanui-loop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/24/kura-omanawanui-loop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This was a great walk. We had been to Whatipu beach before and really liked it there, so decided
to head back and do a walk. We started from Whatipu and took the
&lt;a href="http://regionalparks.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/whatipu/track/Kura%20Track"&gt;Kura track&lt;/a&gt; first. This
track winds its way up through a forest and involved a few stream crossings. At the first of these
there were stepping stones so we spent time trying to get across without getting our feet wet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Great Barrier Island</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/17/great-barrier-island/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/12/17/great-barrier-island/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to go on a trip to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Barrier_Island"&gt;Great Barrier Island&lt;/a&gt; with some friends from work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1425" data-title="Small plane" href="../../2016/12/17/great-barrier-island/001_small-plane.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/12/17/great-barrier-island/001_small-plane_hu_917016c7e9dca300.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Small plane" alt="Small plane" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the first time I had been on a small plane but fortunately the weather was perfect and it was a very smooth ride with some incredible views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1280" data-title="On the way to Great Barrier" href="../../2016/12/17/great-barrier-island/002_flying-over.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/12/17/great-barrier-island/002_flying-over_hu_66fc19e10118ad4a.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="On the way to Great Barrier" alt="On the way to Great Barrier" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Great Barrier we walked to Mount Hobson, starting along &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/auckland/places/great-barrier-island-aotea/things-to-do/tracks/kaitoke-hot-springs-track/"&gt;Kaitoke Hot Springs Track&lt;/a&gt;, then heading east along Tramline Track before heading left at the fork with Peach Tree Track and up to &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/auckland/places/great-barrier-island-aotea/things-to-do/mt-heale-hut/"&gt;Mt Heale Hut&lt;/a&gt;. From there it was a short but very steep up to Mount Hobson and some incredible views over the island.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rangitoto Run</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/6/6/rangitoto-run/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/6/6/rangitoto-run/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We took advantage of a public holiday (the Queen’s birthday) to head over to Rangitoto Island, a
25 minute ferry journey from Auckland. Rangitoto is a volcanic island that last erupted around
600 years ago. We took our running kit and, following a route we found online, ran up to the
summit, did a loop around to some lava caves and back up to the summit again. The views from the
top were amazing, with great views of Auckland and the surrounding area. Not bad for winter.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Haruru Falls Run</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/5/21/haruru-falls-run/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/5/21/haruru-falls-run/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We spent a long weekend in the Bay of Islands for Gemma&amp;rsquo;s birthday and on one day we went for a run to Haruru Falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Mangroves" href="../../2016/5/21/haruru-falls-run/001_mangroves.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/5/21/haruru-falls-run/001_mangroves_hu_bf01b1dd3479ede6.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Mangroves" alt="Mangroves" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way out was on really nice trails through a forest and along a river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1440" data-title="Haruru Waterfall" href="../../2016/5/21/haruru-falls-run/002_haruru-falls.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/5/21/haruru-falls-run/002_haruru-falls_hu_741a155640c5baf2.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Haruru Waterfall" alt="Haruru Waterfall" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the waterfall we saw some chickens chasing each other around the car park.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tongariro Crossing</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months after arriving in New Zealand we travelled south to do the &lt;a href="http://www.tongarirocrossing.org.nz/"&gt;Tongariro Crossing&lt;/a&gt;, supposedly one of the best single day hikes you can do. It was an early start as we had to drop our car off at the finish point and then get a bus to the start. It was very busy due to the good weather and it was also a long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1280" data-title="At the start of the Tongariro Crossing" href="../../2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/001_start.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/3/27/tongariro-crossing/001_start_hu_69db7a15aecbb40e.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="At the start of the Tongariro Crossing" alt="At the start of the Tongariro Crossing" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walk was amazing, passing by active volcanoes, and the scenery was incredible. We were pretty lucky with the weather although there were some low clouds.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Queenstown Hill</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/2/8/queenstown-hill/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/2016/2/8/queenstown-hill/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After two weeks in New Zealand I was lucky enough to go to a conference in Queenstown.
Before the conference started we went for a run/walk up Queenstown Hill, which has some great views overlooking the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="post-photos"&gt;
&lt;a data-index="0" data-size="1920x1425" data-title="Lake Wakatipu from Queenstown Hill" href="../../2016/2/8/queenstown-hill/002_queenstown-hill.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="../../2016/2/8/queenstown-hill/002_queenstown-hill_hu_aa9ad7a550541f78.jpg" class="img-fluid-both rounded mx-auto d-block" title="Lake Wakatipu from Queenstown Hill" alt="Lake Wakatipu from Queenstown Hill" /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id='post-route-0' class="gpx" data-gpx-source="queenstown-hill.gpx" data-map-target='post-map-0' data-title='Queenstown Hill'&gt;
&lt;header&gt;
&lt;a href="queenstown-hill.gpx" title="Download GPX file"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Loading...&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class="start"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;div class="map" id='post-map-0'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;
&lt;ul class="info"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distance:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="distance"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;km&lt;/li&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;li&gt;Duration:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="duration"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;li&gt;Pace:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="pace"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;/km&lt;/li&gt;
&amp;mdash; &lt;li&gt;Ascent:&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="ascent"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;m&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>