<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mountain Bike on The Flying Scotts</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/pr-preview/pr-17/tags/mountain-bike/</link><description>Recent content in Mountain Bike on The Flying Scotts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><managingEditor>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</managingEditor><webMaster>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</webMaster><copyright>2026 The Flying Scotts</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.flying-scotts.uk/pr-preview/pr-17/tags/mountain-bike/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wanaka to Hawea bike</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/pr-preview/pr-17/2021/6/28/wanaka-to-hawea-bike/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/pr-preview/pr-17/2021/6/28/wanaka-to-hawea-bike/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One morning in Wanaka, we hired a couple of mountain bikes and cycled out to Lake Hawea and back.
It was a cold start to the day and took us a long time to warm up.
We set out from Wanaka and cycled along a trail following the edge of the lake.
When we reached the lake outlet the trail passed through a campsite we had stayed in previously, after which it narrowed down for a more technical section.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Niue</title><link>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/pr-preview/pr-17/2018/10/6/niue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>user@example.com (Chris Scott)</author><guid>https://www.flying-scotts.uk/pr-preview/pr-17/2018/10/6/niue/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A belated post about our holiday to the beautiful Pacific island of Niue.
We left Auckland on Saturday on one of the two flights per week (the only flights to Niue from anywhere) and arrived in Niue on Friday, which was a bit strange.
After picking up our hire car (a bit dated) from the airport we headed to the resort.
This was our first encounter with Niue&amp;rsquo;s roads and can be summed up with one word &amp;ndash; potholes!
Nobody seems to drive on the left hand side of the road, instead there are cars swerving all over to avoid the massive potholes that are everywhere.
On the way we passed &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thepuddleniueisland/"&gt;Trevor&lt;/a&gt;, the only duck on Niue, in his pond (large pothole that the fire service top up with water each day).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>